だいたい 今日 お前
出番ないじゃないの！
って そんなｵﾁかよ!!
(さっちゃん)
奥様の名前は さっちゃん｡
ごく普通の結婚をしました｡
勝手に 前話 回想するな！
そして 旦那様の名前は 銀さん｡
(銀時)あんだって!?
(さっちゃん)ごく普通の２人は
ごく普通の恋をし➡
でも ただ １つ違っていたのは
奥様は ﾏｿﾞだったのです｡
The wife's name is Sachan.
The husband's name is Gin-san.
Come again?
They were two ordinary people, who fell in love like ordinary people and married, just like ordinary people.
Stop making up your own recollection of the past episode!
In the first place, you're not appearing in this episode.
But one thing was different: the wife was a masochist.
Hey, are you listening?
Is that your punchline?!
[Tatsuma Sakamoto travels around space as the leader of the Kaientai traders.]
[He was a old friend who fought in the Anti-foreigner War alongside Gintoki, Katsura and Takasugi.]
[Oedo Store Summer Big Sale Drawing]
(神楽)んっ？
Whoa! There it is! Congratulations! You've won first prize!
(おじさん)うぉ～ 出た～！
おめでとうございます！
１等です!!
(ﾃﾚﾋﾞ音声)はるか広がる大宇宙｡
Enjoy the ultimate vacation of dreams and romance in the vast expanse of distant space.
夢とﾛﾏﾝがあふれ 至高の安らぎ｡
大冒険の旅…
そこには すべてがある｡
A vacation adventure with everything.
You'll see the vastness of space as you've never seen it before.
[You, too, can experience the space travel of your dreams.]
あなたは かつて 見たことのない
大宇宙を➡
目にすることになるだろう｡
You know, Gin-san...
Another page in the history of the Milky Way.
(新八)ねぇ 銀さん｡
I'd like to travel around space like that, just once.
ああいう宇宙って
１回 行ってみたいですよねぇ｡
We have many travel plans available. Shake hands with me somewhere in space!
なに言ってんだ ｵﾒｴ｡
宇宙には 空気がないんだぜ｡
What're you talking about? There's no air in space, you know.
If there's no air you'll, you know, die.
空気がねえと あれだ
死んじまうじゃねえか｡
あぁ おかえり 神楽ちゃん｡
Oh, welcome back, Kagura-chan.
Hey, what're you doing?! Becoming a rebel without a cause?
おいおい なにすんだ？
今どき 理由なき反抗か？
どの支配からの卒業ですか？
Who's control did you break free from?
ひざまずくｱﾙ 愚民たちよ｡
(新八/銀時)んっ？
Kneel before me.
頭が高いって言ってんだよ
この貧乏侍どもが！
You're so full of yourselves, you penniless samurai!
Call me "Madame foreman"!
(神楽)工場長と お呼び！
Wouldn't "Queen" be better?
女王様のほうが
いいんじゃねえのか？ 工場長｡
女王様なんかより 工場長のほうが
生産的だから 偉いｱﾙ！
Madame foreman is more productive than Queen, so she's higher!
Call me a slender Madame foreman!
やせこけた工場長 と お呼び！
工場長 ﾄｲﾚｯﾄﾍﾟｰﾊﾟｰ
買ってきてくれた？
Madame foreman, did you buy toilet paper?
ｹﾂふく紙は忘れたけど
もっとｽﾃｷな紙は 手に入れたよ｡
I forgot the paper to wipe your butt with, but I got a much better piece of paper.
(神楽)空を飛べる紙ｱﾙ！
[Patrol Bus Leisure Trip Through Space]
A paper that'll let us fly in the sky.
宇宙の旅 ３名様!?
A trip for three though space?!
こ… 工場長～!!
M-Madame foreman!
(銀時/新八)ばんざ～い！
ばんざ～い！ ばんざ～い!!
Banzai! Banzai!
Banzai! Banzai! Banzai!
["When You're in a Fix, Keep on Laughing, Laughing..."]
(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
Come on, I'm not carrying anything metal.
んだよ 金属のたぐいなんて
持ってねえって｡
あっ もしかして あれか？
Is it responding to my iron will?
心のﾅｲﾌとかにも 反応すんのか？
(係員)現在 攘夷派による犯罪が
多発しておりますので➡
There have been a rash of crimes perpetrated by the Anti-Foreigner faction, so please go through again.
もう一度 お願いします｡
Ah, I know what it is!
あっ そうだ｡
I forgot about the two golden balls between my legs.
股間に２つ 金属ついてんの
忘れてました｡
Sir, if you don't shut the hell up, I'll punch you.
お客様 黙りやがらねえと
殴りますよ｡
姉上も
連れてきてあげたかったなぁ｡
I wish I could've brought my sister along.
宇宙から見た地球は➡
The Earth from space must be so beautiful.
きれいなんでしょう？
神楽ちゃん｡ えっ!?
Kagura-cha...
Ma'am, bringing pets aboard is prohibited.
(係員)お客様 ﾍﾟｯﾄの連れ込みは
禁止になっておりまして…｡
違うよ 人形だよ｡
It's not a pet. It's a doll.
(定春)ﾊｧ～ ﾊｧ～ ﾊｧ～｡
Dolls don't pant.
(係員)人形は ﾊｧﾊｧ言いません｡
No. It's not a doll. It's a humidifier.
違うよ 人形じゃないよ
加湿器だよ｡
(係員)
こんな 生臭い加湿器あるか～!!
Your humidifier smells like rotten meat!
(神楽)じゃあ ﾍﾟｯﾄ｡
はぁ…｡
Okay, it's a pet.
定春 誰にも迷惑かけないし
人にも かみつかないよ｡
Sadaharu won't cause anyone trouble, and he doesn't bite. I guarantee it.
私 保証するｱﾙ｡
He's doing it now! He's doing it right next to you!
(係員)いや やってるから！
言ってるそばから やってるから!!
お客様 大丈夫ですか!?
Sir, are you all right?
(坂本)おい なんじゃ～？
What?
(坂本)気持よく寝ちょったのに
もう ﾌﾗｲﾄの時間かよ～｡
I was having such a nice nap. Is it already time for my flight?
なんか ｽﾞｷｽﾞｷするのぅ｡
昨日 飲みすぎたきに｡
My head is throbbing. Guess I drank too much yesterday.
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
いや 飲みすぎたじゃなくて➡
No, it's not because you drank too much, it's because something's about to swallow you.
今現在 飲まれております｡
(坂本)寝汗も ﾍﾞﾄﾍﾞﾄじゃ｡
I'm covered with sweat.
Huh? It's bright red...
あれ？ 真っ赤じゃ｡
あ～ ﾄﾏﾄｼﾞｭｰｽ飲んだから｡
Oh yeah, I drank tomato juice.
おい～っ！
ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞｼﾝｷﾝｸﾞにも 程があるぞ～!!
Hey! There's a limit to positive thinking!
(坂本)あ～ 体も重いし➡
I feel heavy. This is definitely a hangover.
完全に 二日酔いじゃのぅ｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
Hey, are you listening to what I'm saying?
(係員)ちょっと
人の話 聞いてんの!?
あ～ 定春！
Sadaharu!
なんだ？ あの人｡
What's up with that guy?
♪♪～
(CA)ﾋﾞｰﾌ？ ｵｱ ﾌｨｯｼｭ？
Beef or fish?
ﾋﾞｰﾌ ｱﾝﾄﾞ ﾌｨｯｼｭ！
Beef and fish.
What?
(CA)ﾎﾜｯﾂ？
ﾋﾞｰﾌ ｱﾝﾄﾞ ﾌｨｯｼｭｱﾙ！
Beef and fish!
んで な～に？ 神楽｡
So, Kagura...
定春が 変なﾔﾂにさらわれたって？
I heard Sadaharu got kidnapped by some strange-looking dude?
That's right. I don't think I'll be able to enjoy the trip anymore.
そうｱﾙ！ 私 もう
旅行なんて楽しめそうにないよ！
(神楽)ﾜﾝﾓｱ ﾋﾞｰﾌ ｱﾝﾄﾞ ﾌｨｯｼｭ！
One more beef and fish.
That's why I told you to leave him with the old lady.
だ～から ばばあに
預けておけって言ったんだよ！
I'll have strawberry milk.
いちご牛乳ね いちご牛乳！
もう 台なしじゃねえか 旅行が！
Our trip is ruined from the start.
台なしなのは
お前らの人間性だよ｡
What's ruined is your character.
But I just couldn't leave Sadaharu behind alone.
だって 定春だけ
残していくの かわいそうね｡
Don't you care about Sadaharu, too, Gin-chan?
銀ちゃんは
定春 かわいくないｱﾙか？
旅先で ｷﾞｬｰｷﾞｬｰ
わめくんじゃねえよ！
Don't start bawling again.
あ～ 興ざめだ｡ もう帰るか！
It takes all the fun out of it. I wanna go home.
Passengers, please look out the window on your left.
(機内ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)皆様
左を ご覧ください｡
あれが 太陽系で
最も美しいとされる➡
What you see is the most beautiful planet in the Solar System, our mother planet, Earth.
我らが母なる星 地球です｡
Wow! It's pretty!
わぁ～ きれいだ！
だな～｡
Yeah.
What do you mean, "Wow"! You're having a good time, aren't you?
わぁ～ じゃねえよ！ きっちり
ｴﾝｼﾞｮｲしてんじゃねえか!!
小さな悩みなんて
どうでもよくなってくるな｡
Small troubles don't seem to matter anymore.
Yeah, It really cleanses your soul.
(神楽)ﾎﾝﾄｱﾙ｡ 心 洗われるよ｡
洗っちゃいけないよ！
You don't want it cleansed!
The stains on your soul are the good parts you want to keep!
心に残しておかなきゃいけない
汚れもあるよ!!
まったく…｡ ん？
Good grief...
(犯人)動くな｡
Don't move.
(乗客)ｷｬ～ｯ ﾊｲｼﾞｬｯｸよ！
ﾊｲｼﾞｬｯｸだわ～!!
Hijackers! We're being hijacked!
(犯人)うるせえ 騒ぐな！
Shut up! Nobody move!!
As of this moment, our revolutionary forces
これより この船は
我々 革命組織➡
[Moe Fighting Spirit]
萌える闘魂が 乗っ取った！
"Moe Fighting Spirit," has taken over this ship!
お前らの身代金を
幕府に要求する！
We will demand a ransom for your release from the Bakufu government!!
(犯人)宇宙旅行などという遊興に
うつつを抜かしおって｡
How dare you indulge yourselves on a leisurely trip through space.
The very least you can do is give up your money and contribute to our action fund!
せめて 金を吐き出し
我々の活動資金となるがいい！
Anyone who refuses to give up their money or are too poor,
(犯人)金も出さない不埒なﾔﾂ
貧乏なﾔﾂは➡
will be put to death, no questions asked.
問答無用で くたばってもらう！
We do this in the name of the Earth!
や やばいよ 銀さん 銀さん！
We've got trouble. Gin-san... Gin-san.
When I die, I think I'd like a space burial.
ｵﾚ 死んだら
宇宙葬にしてもらおっかな｡
星になれる気がするわ｡
(神楽)あぁ なれるともさ｡
It would be like becoming a star myself.
Yep, sure would.
お～い!!
ﾎﾝﾄに 星になっちまうぞ～!!
Hey! You both are about to really become stars!
うっ…｡
(犯人)おい ｷｻﾏら➡
You there. What're you doing? Were you listening to what we said?
何をやっている？
我らの話を聞いているのか！
ほわたぁ～!!
(犯人)ｷｻﾏ！
10年 早えんだよ！
Damn you!
You're ten years too young to hijack me!
動くな！
Don't move!
昇龍波!!
ぐおっ！
Amazing!
(乗客)すげえ！
(乗客)ﾗｽﾄｻﾑﾗｲ ﾌﾞﾗﾎﾞｰ！
Bravo, Last Samurai!
ﾜﾊﾊﾊﾊ～！
(神楽)あれ？
Huh?
(犯人)ふざけやがって 死ね～！
…おわっ！
That was a really stupid move! Die!
あ～ 気持悪いのぅ｡
I feel awful.
酔い止めば飲んでくるの
忘れたき～｡ ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
I forgot to take something for this hangover.
(坂本)あれ なに？
なんぞあったか？
Huh? Did something happen?
定春！ この野郎!!
Sadaharu!
You bastard!
あり？
What?
Give Sadaharu back!
定春 返すぜよ～！
定春 よかったよ～！
Sadaharu, I'm so glad you're back!
よ～し よし 怖かったね～｡
There, there... You must've been so scared!
ん？ ｺ… ｺｲﾂは…｡
Th-This guy is...
銀さん 知り合い？
Gin-san, do you know this guy?
(爆発音)
An explosion!
(乗客)爆発だ～!!
The explosion came from the cockpit!
(乗務員)操舵室で爆発が！
操縦士たちも 全員 負傷だ～!!
The pilot and crew are injured!
(騒ぎ声)
終わりだよ お前ら｡
It's all over for you guys.
天人に迎合する売国奴など
みんな 死ねばいいんだ！
All traitors who welcomed the Amanto deserve to die.
(銀時たち)うわぁ～っ!!
お客様！ お客様のなかで➡
Passengers! Is there anyone among you who can pilot a spaceship?!
宇宙船の操縦のできる方は
いらっしゃいませんか！
(乗客)ﾎﾝﾄ 誰でもいいから
助けて～!!
I don't care who, just save us!
(乗客)もう ﾀﾞﾒだ～!!
It's hopeless!
(坂本)ｲﾀｯ！ ｲﾀﾀ！
なにすんじゃ～!?
Ouch! Oww! What're you doing?!
(坂本)誰じゃ!?
ﾜｼを どこに連れていくがか？
Who are you?!
Where're you taking me?
ﾃﾒｴ たしか
船 大好きだったよな？
As I remember, you love ships, right? You can pilot one, right?
操縦くらい できんだろ！
おんしゃ
なんで そげなこと知っちょうか？
How do you know that?
Huh? I've seen you before...
(坂本)あれ？ どっかで見た…｡
Ohh! You're Kintoki! What're you doing here?
お～ お～ お～ おぉ～っ！
金時じゃなかか!!
おんしゃ なぜ
こんなところに おるか？
Long time no see, Kintoki! What a strange place to meet.
久しぶりじゃの～ 金時！
珍しいとこで会うもんじゃ！
酒じゃ！ 酒を用意… うわっ!!
Sake! Someone bring us some sake!
銀時だろうがよ 銀時！
It's Gintoki! Gintoki!!
お前 もし ｵﾚが金時だったら➡
[Note: Kintama is slang for testicles.]
If I were Kintoki, then the title wouldn't be allowed on TV!
ﾀｲﾄﾙ ﾗﾃ欄に載っけらんねえぞ
この野郎！
(艦長)これまでか…｡
This the end... I'm the captain... And I'm going down with my ship.
私も艦長だ 船もろとも死のう…｡
I'll miss Earth, and everything...
地球か… 何もかも 皆 なつか…｡
あれ？ なんか 踏んだがか？
おい 早くしろ！
Huh? Did I step on something?
Hey, hurry up!
(坂本)船に 爆弾仕掛けるなんぞ
どうかしとるぞ｡
Those guys are crazy to set a bomb on a ship.
銀さん やばいですよ！
みんな 念仏 唱えだしてます！
Gin-san, it's not looking good. Everyone's chanting Buddhist mantras.
No need to worry. Leave this in his hands.
心配いらねえよ
ｱｲﾂに任しときゃ…｡
頭は ｶﾗだが 無類の船好き｡
His head's empty, but he loves ships more than anyone.
銀河を またにかけて
飛び回ってるﾔﾂだ｡
He's traveled all across the Milky Way.
To Tatsuma Sakamoto, flying a ship is like moving his own arms and legs.
坂本 辰馬にとっちゃ➡
船 動かすなんざ
自分の手足 動かすようなもんよ｡
Okay, all set.
よ～し 準備万端じゃ｡
Let's do it!
行くぜよ！
You're right. His head is empty.
ﾎﾝﾄだ 頭 ｶﾗだ｡
Hey! Want me to whack you again?
お～い もう１発いくか？
ｱｯﾊﾊﾊ｡
こんな でかい船 動かすの
初めてじゃき➡
This is the first time I've had to pilot a ship this big.
勝手が わからんち｡
I have no idea where to start...
(坂本)舵は どこにあるぜよ？
Where's the ship's wheel?
Gin-chan, is this it?
(神楽)銀ちゃん これは？
これじゃねえことは 確かだよ｡
That's certainly not it!
ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄから 頭 離せ～!!
すんません ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄさん！
Let go of the pilot's head! Sorry, mister pilot.
おいおい やべえぞ！
Hey, this isn't good. We're about to crash into a planet!
なんか どっかの星に
落ちかけてるよ！
銀さん これっすよ これ！
Gin-san, here it is!
ふぐぐぐぐ…！
Huh? It won't budge.
あれ？ びくともしない｡
ﾎﾞｸ でかした！
あとは ﾜｼに任せ… うぷっ！
Well done, son. Leave the rest to me.
ｷﾞｬ～ｯ!! こっち来んな～!!
Don't come near me!
Weren't you supposed to love ships?
ｱﾝﾀ 船好きじゃなかったの!?
You're totally seasick!
思いっきり
船酔いしてんじゃないすか！
I love ships, but riding in them makes me puke.
いや～ 船は好きじゃけれども
船に弱くてのぅ…｡
なに その 複雑な愛憎模様｡
What a complicated love-hate relationship!
新八 もういいから 私に任すよ！
Shinpachi, never mind, let me do it!
私 文集に 将来の夢
ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄ書いたよ！
I wrote an essay in school about how my dream is to become a pilot.
ｵﾒｴは 引っ込んでろ！
もういい ｵﾚがやる！
You stay out of this. Forget it. I'll do it. This is just like driving a mo-ped, right?
こんなもん 原ﾁｬﾘと同じだろ！
No! There's no way I'd leave my life in your hands, even if I had nine lives.
いやっすよ！
ｱﾝﾀらに 命懸けてたら➡
何回 転生しても 足んねえよ！
Hey, hey... Amateurs shouldn't be touching the controls.
(坂本)おうおう！ 素人が
そんなもん触っちゃいかんぜよ！
このﾊﾟﾀｰﾝは
３人で いがみ合ううちに➡
I can see how this is gonna turn out.
The three of you fighting over the wheel is gonna make it break off.
舵が ﾎﾟｯｷﾘっちゅうﾊﾟﾀｰﾝじゃ｡
I've got to prevent that!
それだけは 阻止せねばいかん！
うおっ！
(坂本)ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ～｡
そういうﾊﾟﾀｰﾝで きたか～｡
So this is how it turns out!
ｱｯﾊｯﾊ～ じゃねえよ!!
It's not funny!
(銀時たち)あぁぁぁ～～っ!!
♪♪～
I've made up my mind!
((坂本:決めた！
わしゃ そらに行くぜよ｡
I'm going into space.
(坂本)このまま
地べた はいずり回って➡
If I stay on Earth, crawling around and fighting the Amanto,
天人と戦ったところで
先は見えちょる｡
I know how the future's going to turn out.
ﾜｼらが こうしちょる間にも➡
Even as we speak, the Amanto keep coming and coming.
天人は じゃんじゃん
地球に来ちょるきに…｡
押し寄せる時代の波には
逆らえんぜよ｡
We can't fight the tide of change.
(坂本)こんな戦は いたずらに
仲間 死ににいかせるだけじゃ｡
Fighting this war is only sending our comrades to their deaths.
わしゃ もう
仲間が死ぬとこは見たくない｡
I don't want to see any more of our comrades die.
これからは
もっと高い視点をもって➡
From now on, we've got to look at things from a different perspective.
生きねばﾀﾞﾒじゃ｡
地球人も 天人も➡
A perspective so high, we can see humans, Amanto, and the whole world at once.
いや 星さえも見渡せる
高い視点がのぅ｡
だから わしゃ そらに行く｡
That's why I'm going into space.
そらに でっかい船 浮かべて➡
I'll sail huge ships through outer space...and fish for stars.
星ごと すくい上げる
漁をするんじゃ｡
どうじゃ？ 銀時｡
How 'bout it, Gintoki?
おんしゃ こん狭か星に
閉じ込めておくには➡
You're much too good to stay cooped up on this tiny planet.
もったいない男じゃき｡
ﾜｼと一緒に…｡
Come with me...
(寝息)
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
天よ！ ｺｲﾂに 隕石ば
たたき落としてくださ～い！))
Hey, heaven, send a meteor crashing down on this guy's head.
(笑い声)
はっ！ ｱﾊﾊ… 危ない 危ない｡
I better watch out.
It's so hot, images of the past flashed by like a revolving lantern.
あんまり 暑いもんじゃけ
昔のことが➡
走馬灯のように
駆け巡りかけたぜよ｡
なんとか助かったってのに
危なか～！
At least we managed to survive.
Survive?
助かっただ？ これの どこが
助かったってんだよ！
How is this "surviving"?
一面 ばばあの肌みたいな星に
不時着しやがって｡
We crash-landed on a planet whose entire surface looks like an old lady's wrinkled butt.
ﾃﾒｴが 舵 折りやがったせいだぞ！
And It's all because you broke the wheel back there.
Hey, I've already forgotten the past.
昔のことなんぞ忘れたぜよ｡
Men need only look forward...
男は 前だけ見て
生きていくもんぜよ｡
すっとぼけんな この毛玉～！
Don't play dumb, you hairball!
Oh come on, it's hot, stop shouting.
あ～ もう！ 暑いんだから
大声 出さないでくださいよ｡
神楽ちゃんも 大丈夫？
日が強いし｡
Kagura-chan, are you all right?
The sun is really strong here.
I'm okay. I have my umbrella, so I'm fine.
大丈夫ｱﾙよ｡ 傘があれば 平気ね｡
(神楽)でも のど乾いたから➡
But my throat is dry,
I think I'll go drink some water at that river there.
ちょっと あっちの川で
水 飲んでくるね｡
川って どこ～!?
その川 渡ったらﾀﾞﾒだよ～!!
River? No, wait! Don't cross over to the other side!
とっつあん もう 勘弁してくれ…｡
Daddy, give me a break.
ｵﾚは ﾎﾞｸｼﾝｸﾞなんて
もう どうでもいいんだ｡
I don't care about boxing anymore.
水が飲みてえんだよ…｡
I just want a drink of water.
誰が とっつぁんか～!!
銀さん やばいよ！
Who's your daddy?!
Gin-san, she's not well! Kagura-chan's about to cross the River Styx!
神楽ちゃん 三途の川を
渡ろうとしてるよ！
あ～ しようがねえなぁ｡
(神楽)ｼﾞｮｰ 見逃してくれよ｡
Joe, let me off the hook. I'm just an udon guy.
Guess I have no choice...
(神楽)ｵﾚは どうせ うどん野郎だ｡
お～い しっかりしろ神楽｡
Pull yourself together, Kagura.
All right, Daddy. I'll box to the finish.
わかった とっつぁん｡
やっぱ ｵﾚ ﾎﾞｸｼﾝｸﾞやってみるよ｡
ﾀﾞﾒだ こりゃ｡
目が すわっちゃってる｡
This isn't good. Her eyes are glassy.
あっちの川で 水 飲ましてくらぁ｡
I'll let her drink at that river over there.
You see it, too?!
って お前も見えてんのか～!!
なに言ってんの？
見えねえの？ お前ら｡
What're you saying? You guys can't see it?
あっ 花畑もあるぞ｡
(坂本)おっ おりょうちゃんじゃ｡
There's even a flower garden.
Oh, it's Oryo-chan. Marry me.
(坂本)結婚してくれよ～！
お前ら みんな ﾀﾞﾒ人間か！
Are all of you hopeless?!
ん？ なんだ？ あれ｡
What's that?
んっ？
船だ～！
救援が来た！
It's a ship!
They've come to rescue us!
We're saved!
(乗客)助かったのよ～！
ｱﾊﾊﾊ！ すまんのぅ 陸奥！
Thanks, Mutsu! You came all this way to get me.
こんなとこまで
迎えにきてもらって｡
(陸奥)こんなことは
今回限りにしてもらおう｡
And it'll be the last time I do.
Our ships are for merchant business.
ﾜｼらの船は
商いするためのもんじゃき➡
We can't have you, our leader, always getting into trouble.
かしらの おまんが
こんなこっちゃ困るぜよ｡
(陸奥)それと ﾜｼらに黙って➡
And, this better be the last time you go wandering off without telling us.
ﾌﾗﾌﾗしゆうのも 今回限りじゃ｡
Forgive me. I love Earth women best, after all.
すまんのぅ｡ 女は やっぱり
地球のんが好きじゃき｡
I hope your balls rot off and you die.
ふぐり腐らせて死ね｡
ﾊﾊﾊ～｡ 陸奥は はちきんやき
かなんのぅ｡
I'm no match for a Hachikin like you, Mutsu.
坂本さん これは？
Sakamoto-san, what are these?
Well...
あぁ 快援隊ちゅうてな
ﾜｼの私設艦隊みたいなもんじゃ｡
They're the "Kaientai" fleet I put together.
But they're not for battles.
ちゅうても
戦するためのもんじゃのうて➡
この艦隊 そのものが
ｶﾝﾊﾟﾆｰなんじゃ｡
This fleet is my company.
ｶﾝﾊﾟﾆｰ？
そうじゃ｡
Company?
That's right. We use these ships to engage in big business.
ﾜｼら この船 使って
でかい商い やっちょる｡
(坂本)いろんな星々 回って
品物ば 売り買いしちょる｡
We travel to numerous planets, buying and selling merchandise.
In other words, we're traders.
(坂本)まぁ 貿易じゃ｡
But recently, space has gotten dangerous,
じゃが 近頃 宇宙は
ぶっそうじゃきに➡
こうして 武装も
しちょるわけぜよ｡
so as a self-protective measure, we've armed ourselves with these.
Sakamoto-san, so you're not such a loser after all.
坂本さん ｱﾝﾀ ただの
ﾊﾞｶじゃなかったんですね｡
ﾊﾊﾊﾊ～ 泣いていい？
"Loser"? Can l go cry now?
It's not military might and ideology that motivates people...it's profit!
人を動かすのは 武力でも
思想でものうて 利益じゃ｡
天人 地球人
双方に利益をもたらし➡
Our business profits both humans and Amanto.
関係の調和ば はかる｡
It helps ease tensions between the two.
わしゃあ ﾜｼのやり方で
国を守ろうと思うてのぅ｡
I'm trying to protect our country with my own methods.
へぇ すごいんですね～｡
That's impressive.
まぁ ｳﾁの大将は
ぶらぶらしてますけどね｡
Our boss is always so wrapped up in himself.
(坂本)ｱﾊﾊﾊ！ ﾔﾂは➡
He's harder to pin down than me.
つかみどころのない
男じゃきにのぅ｡
じゃが 人が集まってくる
男っちゅうのは➡
But a man who attracts people to him possesses something special.
何か もってるもんぜよ｡
(坂本)おんしも ﾔﾂのなかの
何かに惹かれて➡
You too, were drawn to something he has inside. Isn't that right?
慕っとるんじゃなかか？
う～ん… なんだか
よくわからないですけど でも…｡
I'm not sure what it is about him...
But...
うあ～っ!!
えっ？ なに？ あれ｡ ｳｿ！
Huh? What? What the? I don't believe it.
ｱﾊﾊ！
いよいよ 暑さにやられたかや｡
I think the heat has finally gotten to me. I'm seeing strange things.
なんか 妙なもんが見えるろ｡
坂本さん！
Sakamoto-san!
ほっとけ ほっとけ 幻覚じゃ｡
Never mind. Never mind. It's just a hallucination.
えっと でも… えぇ～っ!?
Uh...but, uh...
It's okay. Let it be.
ほっとけ ほっとけ 幻覚じゃ～!!
It's a hallucination.
坂本さ～ん!!
Sakamoto-san!
What is that?!
(船員)なんだ あれ～！
(船員)化け物だ～！
A monster!
あれは いったい…｡
あれは 砂蟲｡
What in heaven's name is that?
That's a Sand Bug.
(陸奥)この星の生態系で
頂点に立つ生物｡
It's at the top of the food chain in this planet's ecosystem.
ふだんは静かじゃが➡
It's usually docile. It must have woken up from all that commotion we made.
ｶﾞﾁｬｶﾞﾁｬ騒いじょったきに
目を覚ましたか｡
ちょ… ｱﾝﾀ！ 自分の上司が
えらいことになってるのに➡
What? Now just a minute!
How can you be so calm when your boss is in mortal danger?
なんで そんなに落ち着いてんの!?
勝手なことばかりしちょるから
こんなことになるんじゃ｡
This is what he gets for always going off and doing things on his own.
砂蟲よ！
そのﾓｼﾞｬﾓｼﾞｬ やっちゃって！
Sand Bug! Give that mop-head a good beat down!
Pay special attention to his jewels!
特に 股間を重点的に｡
What? What have you got against him?
なに？ なんの恨みがあんの？
ｱﾊﾊﾊ～！
ﾜｼが こんなところで死ぬか～！
I'm not going to die here!
♪♪～
みんな 逃げえ!!
Everybody get away!
♪♪～
うあ～～っ!!
(笑い声)
♪♪～
で… 出た～!!
H-Here it comes!
うわっ！
It's trying to drag the whole ship down into the sand!
ﾔﾂめ 船ごと
地中に引きずり込むつもりじゃ！
えぇ～っ!?
(坂本)大砲じゃ～！
What?!
The cannons! Send it a greeting with the cannons!
大砲ば お見舞いしてやれ～！
If we do that, Sakamoto-san, you'll be killed, too!
そんなことしたら 坂本さんまで！
(坂本)ﾜｼに かまわんで
ええっちゃ！
Don't worry about me!
B-But Sakamoto-san!
でも… 坂本さ～ん!!
Ready cannons!
砲撃 よ～い！
(船員)砲撃 よ～い！
Ready cannons!
(船員)砲撃 よ～い!!
ｱﾝﾀ 坂本さん 殺す気ですか!?
隊長でしょう!!
Do you want to kill Sakamoto-san? He's your boss!
大儀を失うな｡
Never lose sight of your duty.
ﾔﾂ１人のために 乗客すべてを
危機に さらすわけにはいかん｡
We can't endanger the passengers just to save him.
今やるべきは
乗客の命を救うことじゃ｡
Right now, my duty is to save the lives of the passengers.
大儀を失うな とは ﾔﾂの口癖｡
He always said, "Never lose sight of your duty."
(乗客の悲鳴)
He's a man who left the Anti-Foreigner war and his comrades behind and headed into space.
(陸奥)ﾔﾂは
攘夷戦争も仲間も ほっぽって➡
宇宙へ向かった男じゃ｡
Do you know why he was able to do that?
なんで ほがなことが
できたと思う？
Duty.
大儀のためよ｡
目先の争いよりも➡
He always looked to the future...beyond the battle in front of him.
もっと ずっと先を見据えて➡
And he made the tough decision to labor for the good of his country.
国のために できゆうことを考えて
決断ば したんじゃ｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ～！
We gathered together, drawn by his vision.
(陸奥)そんなﾔﾂに惹かれて
ﾜｼら 集まった｡
じゃから
ﾔﾂの生き方に反するような真似➡
That's why, even now, I cannot flout his principles.
ﾜｼらは できん！
Cannons are ready!
(船員)砲撃準備 よ～し!!
うむ｡ 撃て～!!
Fire!
(爆発音)
それに ﾔﾂは こがなとこで
死ぬ男ではないきに｡
Plus, he's not the kind of guy who'd die from of something like this.
No, no, no! I'm telling you, he's going to die.
いやいや いや！
死んじゃうって あれ！
No matter how you think about it, he's going to die!
どう考えても 死ぬよ あれ～!!
The Sand Bug is escaping under the sand!
(船員)砂蟲が 土の中に逃げるぞ！
No! Sakamoto-san is going to be...!
(船員)いかん 坂本さんが…!!
潜り込む前に 仕留めるんじゃ～！
Kill it before it burrows under!
(船員)坂本さんば救え～！
Save Sakamoto-san!
♪♪～
こんなもん ぶち込むから➡
It's burrowing because you scared it with all that shooting.
やっこさん ﾋﾞﾋﾞって
潜っちまったんだろうが！
大儀を通す前に
ﾏﾅｰを通せ ﾏﾅｰを！
Before you "Do Your Duty"... Remember your manners...
銀さん！
つか おまはんが言いなや｡
Gin-san!
Look who's talking!
辰馬～ ﾃﾒｴ 星を救うとか
でけえことを吐いたくせに➡
Tatsuma! You spun a good story about saving the planet, but is this where it ends?
これで終わりか！
Were you just all talk? Look at me.
昔から ﾃﾒｴは口だけだ！
ｵﾚを見ろ ｵﾚを！
ﾃﾒｴで 考えたとおり
生きてっぞ～!!
I'm living my life on my own terms!
((坂本:そうか…｡
I see...
I thought if you were with me, star fishing would be fun...
お前が おりゃあ
おもしろか漁に➡
なると思うちょったんじゃがのぅ｡
悪いな｡
Sorry about that.
こう見えても この星が好きでね｡
I may not show it all the time, but I like Earth.
宇宙でも どこでも行って
暴れ回ってこいよ｡
Go off to space or anywhere you want and stir things up.
ｵﾒｴには ちんまい漁なんざ
似合わねえ｡
Fishing for small fries doesn't suit you.
でけえ網 宇宙に ぶん投げて➡
Get a humongous net, cast it into space and snag a whole planet.
星でも なんでも
つり上げりゃいい｡
What're you going to do now?
おんしゃ これから
どうするがか？
Me? Well, let's see...
ｵﾚか？ そうさな…｡
ｵﾚは のんびり
ここで 釣り糸 垂らすさ｡
I'll take it easy and cast my net right here.
Maybe I'll catch a shooting star or something... Then release it into the sky.
地べた落っこちた
流れ星でも釣り上げて➡
もっぺん そらにﾘﾘｰｽよ))
《坂本:ﾌﾌｯ｡ そういや～
ほがなこと言うちょったが➡
Yeah, that's what he said...
まったく 何を考えているんだか
わからん男よ｡
Who knows what goes on in that guy's head.
じゃが お前がいたから
わしゃ そらに行けた｡
But it's because you stayed that I was able to journey into space.
You stayed on Earth, so I could move forward without looking back.
お前が 地上に残ってくれたき➡
わしゃあ 後ろば振り返らんと
走ってこれたんじゃ｡
礼ば言うぜよ》
Thank you...
Gintoki...
《坂本:銀時…!?
If you fish me up...every time I fall to the ground...
ﾜｼが 地に落ちるときがきても➡
おまんが また
釣り上げてくれるっちゅうなら➡
ﾜｼは 何度でも飛ぶぞ！
I'll keep on flying
...into the stars!
あの そらに!!》
(みんな)おお…！
(船員)坂本さんじゃ！
坂本さんが 生きちょったぞ～!!
It's Sakamoto-san!
Sakamoto-san is alive!
(陸奥)ﾑﾁｬなことを…｡
That was reckless.
He was almost swallowed up himself.
自分も
飲まれかねんとこじゃったぞ｡
What was that man thinking?
何を考えとるんじゃ あの男｡
ﾎﾝﾄっすね～｡
You said it. What were those two thinking?
なに考えてんでしょう
あの人たち｡
何を考えてるっていうか➡
What were they thinking? They weren't thinking at all.
何も考えてないね｡
♪♪～
でも… なんか あの人らしか
見えないもんがあるのかな｡
But...
is there something that only they can see...?
(笑い声)
[Preview]
Good evening, I'm Pako.
I'm working at a place called the Girly Boy Club.
Please come in, everyone.
Why am I doing this?!
Zura, you too?!
The next episode: "Cute Faces Are Always Hiding Something."
[One of the four Royals of Kabukicho, the Demoness Mademoiselle Saigo.]
[Girly Boy Club is now open for business! Our new girls are Pako and Zurako.]
[Kintama]
It's listed!
あっ！ ﾗﾃ欄 載ってる｡